Desmond Chan

Richmond, BC 778-779-1893 desmondkmchan@gmail.com

PROFILE

Skilled and knowledgeable computer science graduate with 4 years of programming and problem solving experience. In addition to a strong comprehension and retention ability, an aptitude for working in teams has been demonstrated by collaborating with colleagues to complete several assignments and functional projects within a given deadline.

PORTFOLIO

Online Resume

- http://www.desmondchan.ca
 - My online resume website is hosted on an Amazon Web Services Instance using the Node.js Javascript runtime environment as well as the bootstrap framework. This demonstrates an understanding of both back-end and front-end knowledge in programming as well as the ability to include frameworks and libraries to support the languages. I also have integrated CSS media queries and accessibility features that further demonstrate knowledge of User Experience design through responsive web pages.

Portfolio Website

- http://www.desmondchandesign.com
 - Created using Wordpress, this website serves as a more manageable portfolio of project design and development. In addition, this website demonstrates an understanding of security along with search engine optimization through the use of plugins and Google Analytics.

QUALIFICATIONS

- Experience with: C/C#/C++, Java, Python, HTML5, PHP, MySQL, phpMyAdmin, MongoDB, JavaScript, jQuery, Node.js, Angular.js, CSS, SASS, Wordpress, Bootstrap, Amazon Web Services
- Applications: LATEX, Microsoft Office, Eclipse, Microsoft Visual Studio, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Contract Software Developer

Certified Tracking Solutions

June 2015 - October 2015

- Demonstrated strong problem solving skills by individually designing software using Microsoft Visual Studio
 to automate the process of managing and updating the firmware of GPS devices over the air using the
 Jasper Wireless API with no prior industry experience or guidance from a senior employee.
- By automating the updating process, productivity in the workplace increased significantly, as employees no longer had to manually send commands to each individual device and could therefore focus on other tasks.

Quality Assurance Testing Technician

May 2011 - August 2011

- Certified Tracking Solutions
 - Configured GPS hardware and demonstrated detail-orientation by ensuring that the units were functioning properly and had all requested features before shipping them out to the customers, which led to increase in customer satisfaction as well as a decrease in overall complaints and issues with the company products
 - Additionally increased company efficiency through assisting with the product readiness of the mobile devices by packaging the units and ensuring that each order was properly cataloged and ready to ship at any given time.

Desmond Chan Page 2

EDUCATION

Certificate in Web Development

January 2016 - April 2016

Southern Alberta Institute of Technology

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

September 2011 - June 2015

University of Calgary

PROJECTS

School Project: Movie Ticketing Interface

January 2015 - April 2015

University of Calgary

- Further strengthened team communication and task delegation skills by working on designing and creating a movie ticketing interface using Task Centered Design with a group of colleagues
- Demonstrated strong conflict resolution skills by working together to create multiple low-fidelity prototypes and discussing strengths as well as flaws for each before committing to a final version

School Project: Book Management Database

September 2014 - December 2014

University of Calgary

- Collaborated with a group of colleagues to design a database for managing book inventories
- Implemented with PHP using AMP (Apache-MySQL-PHP) architecture.
- Utilized organizational skills to populate the database using myPHPAdmin as well as demonstrating strong attention to detail by focusing on testing the web front-end using mySQL queries in order to ensure that everything was functioning properly, even on unconventional and uncommon user inputs.

RELEVANT VOLUNTEERING EXPERIENCE

Linkages Society March 2015

- Golden Age Club
 - Assisted the elderly with understanding tablet technology by showing them how to use the touch screen as
 well as how to play simple games and therefore demonstrating the ability to explain technical concepts to
 individuals with little to no experience dealing with technology.